Date: 11/03/2019

Hem Chandra Shrivastava

Moble No. +91 9724328633

E. mail ID shrivastava.hem@gmail.com

Respected Sir,

I (Hem Chandra Shrivastava) introduce myself as a Geologist, Passed M.Sc. (Geology) from Banaras Hindu University, Varanasi (UP). Presently I am working in Cement Industry (M/s Ambuja Cements Ltd, Ambujanagar) as a Manager/Geologist (Mineral Resources).

I have 28.7 years total work experience, 4 years as Lecturer in private institute at Patna (Bihar) and 24.7 years experience through in Geological field and Mining) at various Industry & Consultancy.

As per ACL Policy, I will superannuate from the services of the Company on 30/04/2019 after completion of 58 years age.

During the service period, it is very easy to fulfill the requirements of family, but after retirement it is not easy for my future Endeavour.

In view of the above, you are requested to kindly consider my Resume (attached for your kind reference) for a suitable post / post of Geologist in your organization.

I assure you for complete satisfaction to your desired standard and expectation.

I shall remain obliged to you for this act of Kindness.

Thanking You,

Yours Faithfully

(Hem Chandra Shrivastava)

RESUME



Objective:

I (Hem Chandra Shrivastava) introduce myself as a Geologist, Passed M.Sc. (Geology) from Banaras Hindu University, Varanasi (UP). Presently I am working in Cement Industry (M/s Ambuja Cements Ltd, Ambujanagar) as a Manager (Mineral Resources). I have 28.7 years total work experience (4 years as Lecturer in private institute and 24.7 years experience through in Geological field and Mining).

Personal Information:

Name	Hem Chandra Shrivastava		
Father's Name	Late Shri Ramesh Chandra Shrivastava		
Date of Birth	16 th October 1960		
Languages Known	English & Hindi		
Address for Correspondence	Flat No. F/84, (South Colony),		
	M/s Ambuja Cements Limited,		
	Ambujanagar- 362 715, Taluka - Kodinar,		
	District – Gir- Somnath (Gujarat),		
Permanent Address	House No.: A/155, A. G. Colony		
	P.O. Ashiyananagar, Patna,		
	Patna – 800 025 (Bihar)		
Mobile Number	+91 9724328633		
E. mail ID:	shrivastava.hem@gmail.com		
Nationality	Indian		
Sex	Male		
Height	5 feet 4 inches		
Blood Group	B+		
Marital Status	Married		

Academic Qualification:

Examination Passed			Subject	
Master of Science	nce Banaras Hindu University, Varanasi (U.P.)		Geology	
Bachelor of Science Banaras Hindu Universit Varanasi (U.P.)		1986	Geology (Hons.), Geography & Chemistry	
Intermediate of Science Magadh University, Bodh Gaya (Bihar)		1979	Hindi, English, Math, Physics & Chemistry	
Matric Bihar School Examin Board, Patna (Biha		1976	Hindi, English, Math, Physics, Chemistry & Social Study	

Working Experiences:

I have 28.7 years total work experience (4 years as Lecturer in private institute and 24.7 years experience through in Geological field and Mining).

	Description (NA)	V	Name O Address of Earth
S. No.	Description of Work	Year of Service	Name & Address of Employer
1.	Manager (Mineral Resources), engaged in preparation of Mining Plan along with PMCP & FMCP, yearly review & implementation of plans, exploration, quality monitoring and other works (Liasoning) related to State & Central Govt. under Mines and Minerals (Development and Regulation) Act,1957, Rules of MCR, 2016 and MCDR, 2017.	Continue from 24 th November' 2008	M/s Ambuja Cements Limited, Ambujanagar-362 715, Taluka-Kodinar, District-Junagadh (Gujarat)
2.	As Consultant (Geologist & R.Q.P), engaged in preparation of Plans (<i>Mining Plan, Scheme of Mining, PMCP & FMCP</i>) under the Rules of MCR, 1960 and MCDR, 1988.	From April' 1999 to October' 2008	As RQP consultant and qualified Person (under Rule 15 of MCR'2016) total Number of Plans approved: 85
3.	As Geologist, engaged in preparation of Plans (<i>Mining Plan, Scheme of Mining, PMCP & FMCP</i>) & Environment Plan.	From 2 nd December' 1996 to 31 st March' 1999	Paramount Geomin Consultants, White House, Court Chauraha, Udaipur-313 001 (Rajasthan)
4.	As Geologist in Mining & Raw Material Division.	From 1 st July' 1995 to 30 th November' 1996	Sudarshan Minerals & Industries, 1 Ra 41, Gaytry Nagar, Sector-5, Hiran Magry, Udaipur- 313 001 (Rajasthan)
5.	As Geologist in Exploration & Quality Control Division	From 1 st February' 1994 to 31 st May 1995	New India Mining Corporation Private Limited, At & P.ORedi, District- Sindhudurg, Pin Code-416 517 (Maharashtra)
6.	As a Lecturer in private college & working as a Research Scholar "Sedimentological Study on Kaimur Group Formation" around Rohtashgarh, Bihar	From 1989 to 1993	Patna (Bihar) & Ranchi (Jharkhand)

Professional Training:

Course	From	То	Institute/	Details of Training
			Organization	
Mining Plan &	26-12-2001	28-12-2001	IBM, Nagpur	Training Programme on Mining
Mining Scheme			(Maharastra)	Plan & Mining Scheme
				Workshop cum Training
			IBM, Nagpur	Programme on United Nations
UNFC	23-04-2003	25-04-2003	(Maharastra)	Framework Classification (UNFC)
				For Reserve Estimation
Mine Closure Plan			IBM, Nagpur	Training Programme on
	18-05-2004	20-05-2004	(Maharastra)	Preparation of Mine Closure Plan
Implementation of				Registration under Rule 45 of
Rule 45, MCDR	Nov' 2011		IBM, Nagpur	MCDR in Form-M, On line
(Amendment), 2011			(Maharastra)	submission of Returns (Forms-F, H,
				N & O).
Mining Plan			IBM, Udaipur	Workshop on Mining Plan
Guidelines & RQP	June'2013		(Rajasthan)	Guidelines & RQP Examination
Examination				
Mining Plan, Scheme	16-12-2014	17-12-20014	Organized by	Training programme on
of Mining,			Training	"Preparation of Mining Plan,
Progressive mine			Centre IBM,	Scheme of Mining,
Closure Plan and final			Nagpur	Progressive mine Closure Plan and
Mine Closure Plan"				final Mine Closure Plan"
Reserve Assessment	04-08-2015	05-08-2015	Organized by	Training programme on "Reserve
as per UNFC with			Training	Assessment as per UNFC with
case studies &			Centre IBM,	case studies & Preparation of
Preparation of			Nagpur at IBM,	Feasibility Report"
Feasibility Report			Bangalore	

Declaration:

I confirm that the facts stated above at best to my knowledge and understanding.

Thanking You,

Yours faithfully

Place: Ambujanagar (Hem Chandra Shrivastava)

Date: 11/03/2019